Michelle Melton meltonml@appstate. edu (828) 262-7871

Michelle Melton

Web Developer / Programmer

About me I am a Web Developer / Programmer in the Center for Academic Excellence (CAE) at Appalachian State University. My role involves developing and updating the academic web applications used on campus, including the learning management system. Before joining the CAE team, I worked with the Web Services group designing and building academic websites in the Drupal framework.

Prior to coming to work for the university in 2010, I worked for several marketing, advertising, and design companies where I developed experience with marketing and advertising strategy, branding, public relations, project management, graphic design and art direction, as well as web development. I bring knowledge about strategic communication as well as design, usability, and accessibility to the application development CAE provides for campus.

I have a Bachelor of Science in Business Administration and Marketing from the University of Baltimore, I have studied advertising at Maryland Institute College of Art, and I am currently working on a Master of Science in Computer Science at Appalachian State University. My professional interests are focused on web application design and development, and personally I enjoy rock climbing, kung fu, and crossword puzzles.

Experience

April 2015 - present, Web Developer / Programmer Appalachian State University, Boone, NC

- o Modify, integrate, and support academic web applications
- Maintain University LMS (Moodle)
- Program and integrate new features, modify and update existing features within web applications
- Contribute to design and implementation of system architecture for academic web applications
- Provide expertise on design, usability and accessibility for academic web applications and technologically enhanced learning environments
- Interface design for academic web applications

May 2010 - April 2015, Lead CMS Migration Specialist Appalachian State University, Boone, NC

- o Coordinate, plan, design, and develop academic websites (Drupal)
- Build features for University websites
- Assist with development of core University website distribution
- Modify, integrate, and support University web applications
- Educate users on best practices for website design, usability and accessibility
- Support University websites
- Concept and design graphics for campus programs

July 2004 - May 2010, Creative Director Appnet Designs, Boone, NC

- Manage creative and support staff
- Coordinate website projects from sale to completion
- Art direction of all site designs for clients
- Basic server administration
- Implement PHP modules
- Process final site billing and payment
- Design and build layouts for tourism and hospitality websites
- Create banner advertisements for area clients

February 2001 - February 2004, Senior Designer Marriner Marketing Communications, Columbia, MD

- Concept advertising ideas for Kellogg?s Food Away From Home
- o Brand development for Kellogg?s Food Away From Home
- Layout and design of advertising and collateral pieces for Ark Mutual Funds, Carolina Turkey, Cystic Fibrosis, Hershey, Marriott International, Perdue Farms and Phillips Foods

August 1998 - February 2001, Graphic Designer, Account Executive The Cyphers Agency, Annapolis, MD

- o Design print, direct mail, collateral and signage materials
- Create thumbnails for ad layout
- Develop branding campaigns for various clients (logos, brand elements, constants, etc.)
- Layout publication and prepare ad materials for print
- Develop marketing strategies and implement marketing plans for agency clients
- Conduct media research to build marketing plans and budgets
- Control job trafficking for select client and agency projects
- Work with Creative Director to develop targeted ad strategies
- Handle public relations efforts for agency and clients

Education

2017 - present, Appalachian State University

Master of Science, Computer Science

2013 - 2017, Appalachian State University

Continuing Education: Undergraduate Computer Science

1999 - 2000, Maryland Institute College of Art

Continuing Education: Advertising Studies

1995 - 1998, University of Baltimore

Bachelor of Science, Business Administration, Marketing

Honors: Graduation Commencement Speaker, Summa Cum Laude, 4.0 GPA, Dean?s List, Mu Kappa Tau National Marketing Honor Society, Outstanding Marketing Student Award

1993 - 1995, Anne Arundel Community College

Associate of Arts, Marketing

Honors: Summa Cum Laude, 4.0 GPA, Dean's List, Phi Theta Kappa Honor Society, Presidential Scholar Award Recipient

Skills

- HTML
- CSS
- Bootstrap
- JavaScript
- jQuery
- o PHP
- Java
- o C
- o C++
- Assembly
- Bash

- SQL/MySQL
- Linux
- Eclipse/Zend Studio
- Google API
- Drupal API
- Moodle API
- Vim
- Git
- Vagrant
- VirtualBox

- Limited .NET
- Adobe (InDesign, Photoshop, Illustrator, Acrobat, Flash, Dreamweaver, Fireworks, Media Encoder)
- Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Access)
- Google Apps

Accomplishments

- o 2010 Service Award, Appalachian State University
- o Citation of Excellence, Baltimore Addy Awards
- o 2004 Guest Speaker, University of Baltimore

References

References upon request.